Ismail Saoudi

Cell: +1 (513) 713-4001 Email: Ismail.saoudi@icloud.com Location: Cincinnati, OH

Social Media:

LinkedIn: Linkedin.com/in/ismail-saoudi
GitHub: Github.com/ismailsaoudi

Portfolio: https://ismailsaoudi.github.io/Portfolio_IS/

Desired jobs:

Junior Full Stack Web Developer Customer Success Manager Junior DevOps Engineer

SUMMARY:

Junior Full stack web Developer, with +10 years of IT experience driving digital transformation for Fortune 500 companies. Purposeful, customer success, professional focused on building strong processes to improve Customer Adoption, Retention, and Expansion. Proven record of driving customer value, increasing retention, promoting high adoption, and driving upsell and cross-sell opportunities. Holds a master's degree in Computer Engineering. Multilingual and analytical person.

ACCOMPLICHEMENTS AND ABILITIES:

- Built front-end websites from scratch, as well as using ready-made frameworks that enable you to build efficiently.
- Created full-stack single-page web applications using RESTful API routes and AJAX methods, and defined how
 front-end applications communicate with back-end applications and databases.
- Implemented structured and unstructured databases to convert static websites into dynamic websites that persist data.
- Applied the accepted and standard basics of social coding—including source control, issue tracking, and functional feedback—as part of a development community, while building an application.
- Demonstrated strong teamwork and project management skills as a collaborator and independent contributor during the development cycle of complex projects.

EDUCATION:

Full Stack Coding

The Ohio State University - College of Engineering - Columbus Ohio April 2022 - November 2022 Columbus, Ohio

Bachelors in computer science

Higher institute of computer science and communication technology Sousse. September 2006 - July 2011 Sousse, Tunisia

CERTIFICATION:

Cisco Certified Network Engineer: CCNA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Senior Network Engineer

Cintas Corp

January 2021 – current Mason, OH

Application engineer

Werth Inc.

January 2019 - November 2020 Cincinnati, OH

Senior SCADA Engineer

Cypress Creek Renewables Mai 2017 - December 2018 Durham, NC

Integration Manger

Huawei Technologies January 2012 - April 2017 Tunis, Tunisia

RELEVENT SKILLS:

- Azure, GCP
- HTML/CSS/Git
- JavaScript
- BootstrapThe DOM
- APIs
- jQuery JSON AJAX
- Node
- ES6
- Object-oriented programming
- MySQL
- Express
- MVC paradigm

OTHER SKILLS:

- Network Engineering
 Microsoft OS management Tools
 Cisco Certified CCNA
 Computer Science

- Telecom Industry Standards
- Rollout Management
 Blueprint interpretation
 Electronics

- Sequelize

- TestingAgile developmentProgressive Web Apps
- React
- NoSQL
- MERN Stack
- Computer scienceAzure/ GCP/ AWS
- Shell scripting
- Azure VNET
- GitHub /GitLab /Heroku
- Postman / insomnia
 SQL, MongoDB, NoSQL, SQLite
- Azure DevOps pipeline